shareasale.com 2019-10-17

# 1

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Privacy Policy offers you information on how we
deal with your personal and non-personal data – whether you visit our website, whether we collect data
from you as a client (Merchant, Affiliate or Agency) or whether you are a user (visitor of our website or
our clients’ website and platforms). The collection, processing and use of your data takes place in
compliance with all applicable data protection regulations.
Clients confide in us for effectively online marketing their products and services to customers. By
providing our technologies and services we may collect information about your device (a computer,
mobile phone or any other device that you use to browse and enter a website), e.g. its operating system
and browser.
The collection, processing and use of your data takes place in compliance with all applicable data
protection regulations. Highest standards of quality, transparency and openness are the reasons for our
success. The integrity of internet users and in particular data protection are crucial to all our activities.
This privacy policy applies to ShareASale.com, Inc, an Illinois, USA corporation ("ShareASale").
1        Personal Data
Personal data (also “Personally identifiable information”) includes individual information by which you
as a natural person are or can be identified by, e.g. your name, address, telephone number, email
address or date of birth, as well as information which does not reveal your name, but which relates to
you or your device and enables you to be treated individually.
Non-personally identifiable data is information that cannot be connected to your real identity, e.g. the
number of users visiting our website or other any other kind of aggregated information.
ShareASale does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age
of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to
use this website.
2        Collection of personal data and other information
The way you get in touch with us or our technologies and services determine the scope of how we collect
and process personally identifiable information on you or other information. With this Privacy Policy we
want to keep you informed which personal and other kinds of data we receive, why we use it and your
rights in respect of that data. Data as a general term may include all kinds of information such as your
name, your address or information on your device (e.g. your operating system or browser).
2.1      When visiting our website ShareASale.com
This section provides information on how and which data we may collect from visitors of our website
www.shareasale.com.

Our webservers temporarily log traffic data provided by the device you use to enter our website
(including the host name (IP address) of the requesting computer), date, time and duration of your visit,
data specifications of your browser and operating system as well as the name of your access provider,
and the website you were referred from to our website (so called Referrer URL). This information is
stored in a log file until it is automatically deleted in accordance with our retention policy.
The collection and processing of this data is carried out for the purposes of facilitating the use of our
website (connection set-up), understanding how visitors use it and to ensure the security and stability
of our systems as well as the technical administration of the network infrastructure. We do this in the
pursuit of our legitimate interest of maintaining and improving our website and enhancing its usability.
We do not record your name, address, telephone number or email address, unless voluntarily provided
by you, e.g. as part of a survey or when attempting to enter into a contractual relationship.
    2.1.1 Cookies
We use cookies on our website to optimise its usability. Cookies are small text files that are sent from
our servers to your browser to be stored on your device (laptop, tablet, smartphone or similar). Cookies
do not cause damage to your device, do not contain viruses, trojans or other malicious software. The
cookie stores information, which is linked to respective device used. This does not mean, however, that
we store personal information about you or are aware of your identity.
In general, cookies help to improve and optimise the usability of websites and other online services,
including our own websites and online services and those of others. Our use of cookies is strictly
compliant with any applicable cookie and data privacy legislation.
Cookies used on our website are listed below.
  Domain                           Cookie name              Purpose of         the    Cookie    and    further
                                                            information
  *.shareasale.com                 _ga                      Analytic cookies by Google Analytics, please find
                                                            more information here.
                                   _gat
                                   __cfduid                 Server software session cookie
  blog.shareasale.com              PHPSESSID                PHP session id
                                   JCS_INENTIM              Cookie generated by wp-spamshield for anti-spam
                                                            checks
                                   JSC_INENREF              Cookie generated by wp-spamshield for anti-spam
                                                            checks
                                   awinCookieRebrand        Stores the click on the rebranding notice to avoid
                                                            showing you the message multiple times. Cookie
                                                            expires after one year.

Visiting and surfing on our website is possible without cookies. Most browsers accept cookies
automatically. You may alter the security settings of your web browser in order to stop your device
receiving and storing cookies, to allow receiving and storing cookies from selected websites only, or to
be notified before receiving cookies. Please note, however, that these settings may have negative
effects on the usability and user guidance of websites and other online services. You may delete cookies
stored in your browser at any time. Information stored in such cookies will be removed from your device.
    2.1.2 Social Plugins
As ShareASale is participating in social networks, there are some social plugins on our websites which
we would like to inform you about.
Visitors wishing to avoid connecting to plugins used on our websites may install privacy-enhancing
browser plugins, such as Ghostery (https://www.ghostery.com/), NoScript (https://noscript.net/) or
DoNotTrackMe (https://www.abine.com/index.html) etc.
     a. Facebook
Facebook is a social network of Facebook, Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025
(hereinafter „Facebook“). In our online services, we have included different Facebook plugins (for
example, "Like", "Share"). These are marked with the Facebook logo. Depending on the type of function,
additional information may be added (e.g., "Like", "Recommend"). For a summary of all Facebook
plugins please refer to http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/
When you enter a page on our website that contains a Facebook plugin your browser or app will
establish a direct connection to Facebook’s servers where the plugin is loaded from. The information
that your browser has visited the corresponding page of our online services will be transmitted to
Facebook, even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged into your account. This
information (including your IP address) will be sent by your browser directly to a server of Facebook in
the USA and stored there.
If you are logged into your Facebook account at the same time, it is also possible to assign the page
impression to your Facebook profile. If you click on embedded Facebook buttons and log into your
Facebook account (or are already logged in), this information will be sent directly to a Facebook server
and stored there. The corresponding information is published on your Facebook profile and in your
chronicle/timeline in short form. Facebook can thus collect and store additional usage data. If you want
to prevent the transmission and storage of your data and your behaviour on our online services through
Facebook, you must log out of your Facebook account before you visit our sites and delete any cookies
placed by Facebook. You can also prevent the loading of the Facebook plugins with add-ons for your
browser, e.g. with the online "Facebook Blocker".
For more information on your rights and on how Facebook is recording and processing data please see
Facebook’s Data Privacy Policy which is available at http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ and
https://www.facebook.com/help/443483272359009#!/help/340599879348142/.
     b. Twitter
Twitter is a microblogging service of Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA
94103, USA (hereinafter “Twitter”). Twitter plugins on our websites are usually marked with Twitter’s
logo which is a little bird.

When you enter a page on our website that contains a Twitter plugin your browser will directly connect
to Twitter’s servers where the plugin is loaded from. The information that you (including your IP address)
have visited our online services will be transmitted to Twitter, even if you are not logged into your
account. If you are actively using a Twitter plugin, Twitter may even process more data and publish
content that you are entering into the dialogue box (“twittering”). This allows Twitter to map the visit of
our pages to your user account. We would like to point out that as a provider of the pages we are not
aware of the content of the transmitted data as well as their use by Twitter.
If you want to prevent the assignment of your visit of our websites to Twitter, you must log out of your
Twitter account before you visit our site and delete any cookies placed by Twitter.
For more information on your rights and on how Twitter is recording and processing data please see
Twitter’s Privacy Policy which is available here: https://twitter.com/privacy/. You can change your privacy
settings in the account settings of your Twitter profile at http://twitter.com/account/settings. HYPERLINK
"http://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/"HYPERLINK                                              "http://en-
gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/"HYPERLINK "http://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/"
     c. LinkedIn
LinkedIn is a social network of LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043,
USA (hereinafter „LinkedIn“). LinkedIn's plugins are integrated on this website. You can recognize the
LinkedIn plugins through the LinkedIn logo or the "Share" button on this website. When you visit this
website, the plugin is used to establish a direct connection between your browser and the LinkedIn
server. The information (which online service was being visited) is transmitted to Linkedin, even if you
are not logged into your Linkedin account.
If you click on the LinkedIn "Share Button" while being logged into your LinkedIn account, you can link
the content of this website on your LinkedIn profile. This allows LinkedIn to map the visit of this website
to your user account. For details on data collection (purpose, scope, further processing, usage), as well
as      your     rights    and     settings,    please      refer     to     LinkedIn's   Privacy     Policy
http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy&trk=hb_ft_priv.
All social media plugins are used in the pursuit of our legitimate interest of marketing our business and
communicating with our business partners and the public.
    2.1.3 Analysis: Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics which is a web analysing tool of Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain
View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter “Google“) for the purposes of the adequate design and continuous
optimization of our website. Google Analytics works with cookies and creates pseudomonysed usage
profiles, which enable an analysis of your use of our website. Information stored in such cookies (such
as browser type/version, operating system used, referrer URL, Hostname of the accessing computer,
time of server request) are usually transmitted to and stored on Google’s servers in the USA. We do this
in the pursuit of our legitimate interests of better understanding how our website is used and to report
aggregated usage statistics.
Due to the activation of the IP anonymization (IP masking), Google will truncate and therefore
anonymize the IP address of your device within the European Union or the European Economic Area.

We contracted Google to analyse your use of this website in order to produce reports on the activities
on our website and provide more services connected to the use of our website and the internet in
general. The IP address provided by your browser will not be combined with other Google data. The
information may be transferred to third parties if this is required by law or if third parties process this
data on behalf of Google. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your device by adjusting your
browser software accordingly. Please note, however, that changing your settings may have negative
effects on the usability of our website. You may prevent Google from recording and processing data on
your use of our website (including your device’s IP address) and storing such information in a cookie by
downloading         and         installing    a       browser        deactivation        add-on       from
http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.
For more information, see Google's privacy policy: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.
2.2      When you are our client or becoming one
    2.2.1 Registration in our Network
You need to register in our Network in order to obtain access to our technologies and services as
contractually agreed upon. If you enter into a contractual relationship with us and/or register in our
Network, we record all data, including personal data, which has been provided by you such as your
name, address, telephone number or email address. You can see from our online registration form which
personal data in detail we record. We do not record any further personal data other than voluntarily
provided by you (e.g. as part of a survey or a request for information).
We may also collect information on the device you are using to enter our User Interface page (…) such
as your operating system and browser of your device.
We use all such data in order to comply with our obligations under agreements with users of the
marketplace or the UI, or in the pursuit of our legitimate interest of fraud prevention and the proper
administration of our business.
    2.2.2 Cookies in the User Interface
We use cookies on our User Interface pages with the purpose of pursuing our legitimate interests of
improving and optimising usability for our clients.
Cookies used on our User Interface pages are listed below.
  Domain                    Cookie name                                 Purpose of the Cookie and further
                                                                        information
  *.shareasale.com          FeaturedCampaign<merchantid>                Set on affiliate browser for tracking
                                                                        merchant featured program signups
                            userid                                      Numeric affiliate identity
                            merchantid                                  Numeric merchant identity

                          opm                                    Numeric OPM identity
                          ariddle                                Encrypted affiliate authentication
                          mriddle                                Encrypted merchant authentication
                          oriddle                                Encrypted OPM authentication
                          SHRSL_ID                               Identity traced for account sign ups
                          express                                User preference to redirect to the login
                                                                 page
                          SignupCampaign<merchantid>             Set on affiliate browser for tracking
                                                                 merchant sign up campaigns
                          HC                                     Depreciated UI preferences cookie
                          atoken                                 Demo affiliate account session token
                          mtoken                                 Demo       merchant   account   session
                                                                 token
                          shsc                                   Authorization cookie for merchant and
                                                                 affiliate accounts
                          HolidayFeaturedCampaign<merchantid>    Set on affiliate browser for tracking
                                                                 affiliate sign up campaign
                          __utma                                 Analytics cookies by Google, more
                                                                 information available here.
                          __utmb
                          __utmc
                          __utmli
                          __utmt
                          __utmz
  2.2.3 Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics which is a web analysing tool of Google Inc. on our User Interface pages.
More information is available here.

    2.2.4 Newsletter
With the following information, we will inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the
registration, dispatch, statistical evaluation procedure and your right of objection. By subscribing to our
newsletter, you agree to the receipt of the newsletter and the procedures described. We do this in the
pursuit of our legitimate interest of marketing our business.
We send out newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications with promotional information
(hereinafter "Newsletter") subject to the consent of the recipient or a legal permission.
The registration for our newsletter is handled through a so-called double opt-in procedure, which means
you will receive an e-mail after your registration, in which you will be asked to confirm your registration
once again. The registrations for the newsletter are recorded in order to prove the accurate registration
process according to legal requirements. This includes storing the time of logon and confirmation.
Furthermore changes to the data stored by Mailchimp are being recorded.
The newsletter will be sent by means of "MailChimp", a newsletter platform of the US company Rocket
Science Group // 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA or "Cheetah Digital”,
a newsletter platform of the US company Experian Information Solutions, Inc // 475 Anton Boulevard,
Costa Mesa, CA 92626 United States.The e-mail addresses of our newsletter recipients, as well as
further data described in the context of this information, are being stored on the servers of MailChimp in
the USA. MailChimp uses this information to send out and evaluate the newsletters on our behalf. In
addition, MailChimp can use this data to optimize or improve its own services, e.g. for the technical
optimization of the dispatch and the presentation of the newsletter or for economic purposes in order to
determine from which countries the recipients come from. However, MailChimp does not use the data
of our newsletter recipients to contact them independently or transfer data to third parties.
MailChimp is certified under the US-EU-Data-Privacy-Agreement the "Privacy Shield" and is committed
to comply with EU data protection requirements. Furthermore, we have concluded the "EU Model
Clauses" with MailChimp. This is a data protection agreement which obliges MailChimp to protect the
data of our users, to process according to its privacy regulations on our behalf and in particular not to
pass data on to third parties. You can view the privacy policy of MailChimp here:
https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/.
In order to register for the newsletter, we only need your e-mail address. Further voluntarily provided
information about you is only used to personalize the newsletter.
There are cases where we direct the newsletter recipients to the MailChimp websites. E.g. our
newsletters contain a link with which the newsletter recipients can access the newsletters online (for
example in the case of display problems in the e-mail program). Furthermore, newsletter recipients can
subsequently change their data (like their e-mail address). Likewise, the data privacy policy of
MailChimp is only available on their website.
You may terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, which means revoke your consent.
Therewith your consent to the dispatch of the newsletter via MailChimp as well as the statistical analyses
expire at the same time. A separate cancellation of the dispatch via MailChimp or the statistical
evaluation is unfortunately not possible. You will find a link to unsubscribe from our newsletter at the
bottom of each newsletter.

2.3      When using our technologies and services via websites and
         online services of our clients
2.3.1 Our Tracking | Use of Cookies
We use cookies to provide our tracking services, which also include our reporting services. Please find
some general information on cookies here.
Tracking allows us to understand which website referred a user to another website, so that the second
website can acquire more website traffic. We measure the success of these referrals and assist the
payment of commissions from the website receiving the traffic to the website referring that traffic.
We store cookies on devices of users who are visiting websites and using online services of our clients
in order to record business transactions (leads and sales such as signing up for a newsletter or placing
an order in a web shop). The only purposes of our tracking cookies are to allocate one successful
advertisement to a particular business transaction, and to perform corresponding billing services.
Personally identifiable information on the user are neither collected nor processed nor used in tracking.
Nothing but the information when and on which device a click on an advertisement occurred is stored in
tracking cookies. We only store an individual sequence of figures that cannot reveal the name of a
particular user and contains information on
     -   the Merchant’s Partner Programme
     -   the Affiliate
     -   the specific time of the user’s action (click or view)
While tracking we may also collect information on the device that is used to perform a business
transaction such as the device’s operating system and browser.
We collect this data ourselves and share this data with Merchants, Affiliates and Agencies which use
our network from time to time. We also receive this data from those entities.
Our tracking cookies are listed below.
  Domain                          Cookie name          Purpose of the Cookie and further information
  *.shareasale.com,               <merchantid>c        Encoded userid, tracking gap, & click data
  *.shareasale-analytics.com      <merchantid>o
                                  <merchantid>u
                                  sscid                Base 36 encoded date & hit id data
                                  sstid
                                  XD<0-39>             Data structure containing tracking data; userid, click id,
                                                       expirations

                                   xaj                For merchants with advanced analytics enabled, a
                                                      comma delimited list <merchantid>=<timestamp>
                                   xsj                Comma delimited list of encoded data structures
                                                      containing affiliate id, expiration, and click data
                                                      references
                                   xdj                Comma delimited list of merchant ids
You may alter the security settings of your browser in order to limit the use of cookies on your device.
You may choose to stop your device receiving and storing cookies at all, to allow receiving and storing
cookies from selected websites only, or to be notified before receiving cookies. Please note, however,
that these settings may have negative effects on the usability and user guidance of websites and other
online services. You may delete cookies stored to your browser at any time. Information stored in such
cookies will be removed from your device.
    2.3.2 Information on Cookies and Third Party Cookies
In contrast to “normal” cookies (so-called first party cookies), which are mostly used by the website
operator itself, third party cookies are cookies from a third party that place their cookies on the website
of another website operator. As a Affiliate you may be obliged – depending on the jurisdiction you are
active in – to inform users of your website about cookies that are used on your website, including such
placed by ShareASale (as so called third party cookies). This obligation to provide information also
includes information on the purpose of the cookie and how the user may prevent cookies being placed
on his/her device. A user must give his/her consent to the use of cookies on the Affiliate’s website,
before a cookie is placed, either by the Affiliate or a third party. The Affiliate who operates the website
is responsible for receiving this consent which shall include the consent regarding cookies placed by
ShareASale. Please see here for a list and description of cookies used for tracking purposes by
ShareASale.
    2.3.3 General
The above processing is undertaken in the pursuit of our legitimate interests of operating our affiliate
networks, generating revenue and fraud prevention.
We control how data is processed for the purposes of tracking alongside the Merchants and Affiliates
which use our network from time to time.
3        Processing and use of personal data
We use personal data provided by our clients only for administrating and providing our technologies and
services, for responding to clients’ enquiries and, where applicable, executing the contract between a
client and ShareASale. We store personal and any other kind of data strictly in compliance with

applicable data protection and privacy legislation and our contractual duties, and will prevent
unauthorized access to data to the best of our abilities.
Provided you have given your consent or have not objected – where legal provisions allow so – we may
use your personal data for advertising and market research. By registering with our Network you give
your consent that we may contact you via telephone, via mail and email in order to provide you with
information on ShareASale offers. You may withdraw your consent at any time.
We may transmit your data to our subcontracted service providers, both in and out of the US, but only
if we contractually assigned these to process data on our behalf and, both ourselves and the
subcontracted service providers comply with all requirements of commissioned data processing
regulations.
In order to fulfil our contractual obligations we may transmit your data to companies that we control and
subsidiaries of such provided that these companies are subject to this Privacy Policy or privacy
guidelines ensuring at least equal protection for your data.
We do not transmit data to other third parties unless you have given your consent thereto or the
transmission is made to state institutions on the basis of mandatory national legislation.
4        Data security
ShareASale takes all technical and organisational security measures required to protect your personal
data from loss, unauthorised disclosure or other forms of misuse. Data is stored in a safe environment
that is not open to public access. Your personal data may be encrypted before transmission in certain
cases (e.g. processing your login data). This means that – support by your browser provided –
communication between your device and our servers will include recognized encryption measures.
Our staff has been trained in privacy matters and in dealing with data and information, which they gain
access to in a responsible manner.
Please be aware that should you contact us via email, confidentiality of information therein may not be
ensured. Third persons may have access to contents of emails.
5        Individual Rights, Access, rectification, deletion and
         blockage
You have the right of access to some categories of your personal data at any time and may request
rectification or erasure of your data. You may also object to data processing. Where you have given
consent to any processing, that consent may be withdrawn at any time.
In case you registered as a client on our website, you may use your client account to exercise some of
these rights..
You may exercise your legal rights by contacting us on our details set out in paragraph 7.

If you are not happy with our processing of your data, you may make a complaint to your local data
protection regulator.
While observing applicable privacy legislation we will erase your data without any action required by
you, if retention of your data is no longer necessary for the purpose pursued or retention is no longer
allowed for any legal reason. We may restrict processing instead of erasing your data where legally not
allowed to erase (e.g. legal obligations to maintain your personal data).
6        Amendments
We may modify this Privacy Policy and our data security provisions from time to time, in particular if new
laws and regulations need to be adopted or we regard amendments reasonable. The date of
amendments will be posted below the heading of this Privacy Policy.
7        Questions / Contact
ShareASale is a wholly owned subsidiary of Awin AG, a company registered in Germany (Eichhornstr.
3, 10785 Berlin, GERMANY).
Please bring any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, requests for further information on how we
process your data, suggestions and possible complaints to the attention of the Group Data Protection
Officer of AWIN AG via email: global-privacy@awin.com, fax: +49(0)30 50 96 91-99 or mail: AWIN AG,
Eichhornstr. 3, 10785 Berlin, Germany.
